redbullmediahouse.com 2014-11-21

# Privacy Policy - Red Bull Media House

Red Bull Media House: Data Protection and Privacy Policy  
(last updated on 23rdOctober 2012) 

1\. Introduction  
Red Bull Media House GmbH, Oberst-Lepperdinger-Str. 11-15, 5071 Wals near Salzburg, Austria (hereafter “We”, “Us” and “Our”) respects Your right to privacy. This Data Protection and Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”), together with Our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.redbullmediahouse.com/terms-and-conditions.html "Opens internal link in current window"), explains how We use Your personal information and data collected from the Website and Your rights in respect of such information and data. Capitalised terms which are used in this Privacy Policy have the meanings given to them in Our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.redbullmediahouse.com/terms-and-conditions.html "Opens internal link in current window").  
Personal information provided by You or gathered by Us is controlled primarily by Us as data controller pursuant to the [Datenschutzgesetz 2000](http://www.dsk.gv.at/ "Opens external link in new window") (Data Protection Law Austria, 2000). 

2\. What information do We collect?  
We collect and process the following information about You:

  * information We learn about You from Your use of the Website and Content and Services offered by Us;
  * details of any transactions You carry out through the Website; and
  * information You provide when giving Us feedback and Content.

3\. For what purposes do We use the information We collect?  
We use personal information collected from You for the following purposes:

  * to provide Our Content, Services and products;
  * to improve and personalise Website, Content, Services and products;
  * to research Our Website, Content, Services and products;
  * to ensure that the Services and Content are relevant to You;
  * to deliver and provide You with Our Content or Services;
  * to carry out auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and enhance the Content or the Services We provide; and
  * to transfer Your details to relevant third parties, public bodies, competent authorities, industry organisations, collection agencies, regulators, assignees as reasonably required for the operation of Our business and in the event of a merger or acquisition.

We may also monitor Your usage of the Website, and Content or Services You receive, request or provide when using the Website for the purposes of quality control. 

4\. How do We store and when do We transfer Your personal information?  
All personal information that You submit via the Website is sent to and stored on secure servers located in the European Union. Information submitted by You may be disclosed by Us to other companies within the Red Bull Group and/or to the third parties mentioned in the circumstances described below, which may be situated outside the European Union and/or may be processed by staff operating outside the European Union. We use third party vendors, hosting and service partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage and related technology to run the Website. By submitting information via the Website, You agree to this storing, processing and/or transfer. 

5\. Disclosure of Your information  
We may share the information We collect among. Our affiliated companies at home and abroad including Our partners, joint ventures and with any future owners of the Website. 

We may from time to time employ other companies and individuals to carry out functions on Our behalf including delivering services, providing marketing assistance, analysing dataand invoicing purposes and enforcing Our Terms and Conditions. In order to carry out their functions these companies and individuals may require access to Your personal information but We shall only disclose such relevant personal information as is needed by them to perform their functions. Where requested to do so, We may co-operate with any court, tribunal, regulatory body, police authority or other similar authority in any investigations or proceedings concerning You or Your use of the Website.  This may include disclosing information about communications transmitted via the Services to the authorities where required.  
Whilst We take measures to safeguard the personal information that You provide to Us, no transmission over the Internet can ever be guaranteed secure. Consequently, please note that We cannot guarantee the security of any personal information that You transfer to Us over the Internet. 

6\. Tracking Software and Cookies – What are they and how do We use them?  
We may use Our own and third party tracking software to help Us analyse Your use of the Website, Content and Services.  Such analytical tools use cookies which are text files placed on Your computer’s hard drive by the Website that collect certain information and data about You and Your visits to the Website, such as Your IP address, browser type, the time and length of Your visit, the pages of the Website You visit and other clickstream data. Using this information enables Us to tailor Our Services to You and make Your use of the Services more user friendly and efficient.  
Most internet browsers allow You to erase cookies and tracking software from Your computer’s hard drive, receive a warning before they are stored, or to turn off the cookie or tracking software altogether. If You want to know how to do this please refer to Your browser instructions or help screen, but please be aware that if You refuse cookies or tracking software it may lead to a decreased level of functionality of the Website. 

Google Analytics  
is one of the tracking software We use, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ). Google Analytics also uses “Cookies”. The information generated by the Cookie about Your use of Our Website (including Your IP- address) will usually be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the USA. In case of the activation of IP-anonymisation on Our Website though, Your IP-address will be shortened by Google within a member states of the European Union or within other states that are parties to the European Economic Area Agreement. Only in exceptional cases will Your IP-address be fully transferred to a server of Google in the United States and be shortened there. Google will use this information on Our behalf for the purpose of evaluating Your use of the Website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google will not associate Your IP-address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of Cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on Your browser, however please note that if You do this You may not be able to use the full functionality of Our Website. You can also prevent the acquisition of the data generated by the Cookie (including Your IP-address) by downloading and installing the browser-plugin available by the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. You can find further information here: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html>. 

Webtrends Analytics  
is another of the tracking software We use, also a web analytics service provided by Webtrends Inc. (851 SW 6th Ave. Suite 1600, Portland, OR 97204, USA) Webtrends tracks and analyzes non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from Our Users. All data collected by Webtrends on Our behalf is owned and used by Us. For more information about how Webtrends collects data, please read their privacy policy at <https://ondemand.webtrends.com/privacypolicy.asp#PSFV>. 

7\. Your rights  
You have the right to obtain a copy of processed personal information and data held by Us about You. You also have the right to ask Us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal information that We hold about You.  If You would like to obtain a copy of Your personal information, notify Us of any inaccuracies in the information We hold about You, or if You have any queries concerning Our Data Protection and Privacy Policy, please write to Us at: Red Bull Media House GmbH, Oberst-Lepperdinger-Str. 11-15 in 5071 Wals near Salzburg, Austria or send an e-mail to: [info@at.redbullmediahouse.com](mailto:info@at.redbullmediahouse.com "Opens window for sending email"). For Your own data safety You will need to verify Your identity and specify what information You require. In order to cover Our costs incurred in providing You with a copy of Your information We may charge You a fee. 

8\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy without prior notice. You should continue to check this Privacy Policy for updates and amendments, as You will be deemed to have accepted any changes if You continue to use the Website after they have been posted. 

10\. Language  
The original version of this Privacy Policy is in English language. Any translated version is for Your convenience and information only. In case of disputes the English text shall prevail. 

© 2012 Red Bull Media House GmbH
